자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
안녕하세요
여기 괜찮은데요
오늘 밤 정말 멋졌어요
8년째예요
Eight years.
그래, 사람들은 우리가
오래가지 않을 거라 했지
And people said we wouldn't last.
결혼기념일 축하해, 여보
Happy Anniversary, baby.
결혼기념일 축하해요
Happy Anniversary.
피해자가 둘
Two victims.
여자는 인도 가장자리에
남자는 길 가운데 있어
She's on the side-walk, a foot from the curb.
He's in the middle of the street.
뭐가 없지?
What's missing here?
차가 없군
No car.
자비도 없어
No mercy.
이 남자 최소한 5번은 찔렸어
This guy was stabbed at least five times.
붉은 색 털을 찾았어
Got some reddish hair.
피살자 머리카락은 갈색이군
Vic's hair is brown.
뭐 좀 알아냈나요?
What have we got?
그들은 '안드레'라는 식당에서
저녁을 먹었어
They had dinner at Andre's.
신용카드와 식당에 있는
신용 카드 영수증이 일치해
The card is consistent
with his credit card receipt.
종업원에게 차 빼달라고
안 시켰군요
Didn't bother to valet.
5달러 아끼려다 목숨을 버렸어
차량절도사건이 크게 되어 버렸어
Saved five bucks, but cost them their lives.
Car-jacking gone bad.
차량절도범은 칼을 쓰지 않죠
Car-jackers don't use knives.
절대로?
Never?
일요일은 아닐 거라고 했지만
그러다 진주만에서 당했죠
They used to say never on a Sunday.
Then, Pearl Harbor happened.
전 '절대'란 말을 절대 안 써요
I never say never.
이런
Oh man,
3분 안에 사건현장을 처리해야 돼
we have three minutes to
process this crime scene.
그 뒤에는 모든 것이
비에 씻겨 하수구로 흘러가!
After that, we lose it all to the gutters!
새라, 방수막을 쳐!
Sara take overalls.
워릭, 가방에 담은
증거물 위치에 콘 세워놔!
Warrick, throw cones down
on everything you bag!
닉, 차에다 시신들을 실어
We gotta get these bodies into the van.
자! 어서 하자고! 어서!
재킷 들고 있어요
- Let's go guys.
- Keep the jacket up. / Let's go
시신 주머니 갖다 줘
이 여자시신 덮을 거야
Bring me a body bag,
I wanna cover this wallet.
다른 들 것 있어요?
Can we get another gurney.
들 것이 더 필요해
I need another gurney.
이것 싣자고
어서 합시다, 어서
- Let's go. Let's go.
- Yeah, I got it.
어, 했어
좋아, 이 남자 올려놔
자자, 이봐
서두르라고
Come on, hurry up.
비닐로 덮어
Get the plastic on.
모든 게 엉망이 됐어요
We're losing everything.
그래, 살인범 오늘 운 좋군!
Yeah, our killer got lucky tonight.
CSI : Crime Scene Investigation
1x18 35k O.B.O.
월리암 피터슨(길 그리섬役)
CSI 레벨 3(반장), 전문분야 : 곤충학
마그 헬겐버거(캐서린 윌로우스役)
CSI 레벨 3 , 전문분야 : 혈흔 분석
게리 도단(워릭 브라운役)
CSI 레벨 3, 전문분야 : 음향/시각 자료분석
조지 이즈(닉 스톡스役)
CSI 레벨 3, 전문분야 : 머리카락, 섬유질 분석
조자 폭스(새라 사이들役)
CSI 레벨 3, 전문분야 : 물질성분 분석
폴 길포일(짐 브래스役)
라스베가스 시경
싱크편집
송미혜(smh8119@nate.com)
한글번역
이승조(iceofire@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON CBS: 2001/03/29
이런! 비가 와서 DNA 자료 얻을 수
있는 모든 기회를 날려버렸어
Well, the rain screwed up all our
chances for a good DNA profile.
담지 않아도 될 거야
좋은 생각이야
- Hey, don't even bother bagging it.
- Good idea.
여기 테이프 좀 더 줘
I've got some more tape in here.
목격자는 없나요?
We got any eyeballs?
조용한 거리고 평일 밤이야
주변 이웃들은 소리만 들었어
Quiet street. Week night.
Residents heard the commotion.
저기 저 학생이 유일한 목격자야
The kid over here had the only view.
학생, 이름이 뭐지?
What's your name, son?
저스틴 그린입니다
Justin Green.
저스틴, 난 길 그리섬이고
이쪽은 새라 사이들이네
Well Justin. My name is Gil Grissom,
this is Sara Sidle.
과학수사대에서 나왔어
We're with the Crime Lab.
이건 자네 핀가?
Is, ah, that your blood?
아뇨, 실려 간 남자시체의 피예요
No, uh it's his, the one you took away.
전 도우려 했어요
잘되게 하려고 했는데
I tried to help him.
I thought I was doing everything right.
제가 죽인 것 같아요
I think I might have killed him.
진정하게
Whoa, slow down.
정확하게 어떻게 했지?
What did you do exactly?
길을 건너고 있는데 SUV가 갑자기
나타났어요, 절 칠 뻔 했죠
I was crossing the street and this SUV
came out of nowhere. I almost got clipped.
돌아보니 그가 길에
쓰러져 있었어요
I turned and there was
this body lying in the street.
오, 맙소사!
Oh, my god!
여기 도와줘요!
Help! Help!
누가 911 불러요!
Somebody call 911.
흥분해서
I freaked.
엉망으로 했어요
I did everything wrong.
머리를 젖히지 않았고
I didn't tilt his head back.
기도를 유지하지도 않았어요
I didn't clear his airway.
위로가 될지 모르겠지만
그게 사인은 아니야
If it makes you feel any better,
that's not what killed him.
저스틴, 네 옷 좀
가져갔으면 하는데
Justin, we're going to need
to take your clothes.
왜요?
Why?
옷이 피투성이잖아
Because there's blood all over them.
캐서린?
안녕하세요?
Catherine. / Hey.
머리 괜찮은데
고마워요
Like the hair! / Thanks.
여긴 어쩐 일이야?
What are you doing here?
이 사건 배정받았어요
I was assigned. This is my case.
사건이라고?
Case?
그냥 건물이 무너진 거고
범죄사건 같은 건 아닌데
The building collapsed.
There's nothing criminal here.
그래서 살인사건 담당형사가
이 사건 배정받았나요?
Right. That's why you were assigned
a homicide detective.
어떻게 된 거죠?
What happened?
지하실 일부가 함몰되었고
나머진 따라 꺼져버렸지
Well, part of the basement caved in.
Brought the rest down with it.
시신 수는요?
Body count?
여자 노인 세 군데 자매야
Three old women. Sisters.
'행운의 바퀴'를 보다가 순식간에 당했지
[Wheel of fortune: 29년 된 미국 인기 게임 쇼]
One minute you're watching Wheel of Fortune.
Next thing, game over.
그래서 범죄현장이
아니라는 거예요?
And you're not calling this a crime scene?
캐서린, 이건 그냥 건물일 뿐이야
Catherine, it's a building.
오라일리 형사님
O'Riley,
이건 용의자예요
it's a suspect.
안녕, 그렉
Hey, Greg.
잠깐만요, 애 엄마가
될지도 모를 사람 거예요
SSh. I might be looking at
the mother of my children here.
일을 너무 많이 해서
상태가 안 좋아졌군
Somebody's been putting in
way too much overtime.
아뇨, 이거 장난이 아니에요
No. This is serious.
어젯밤에 데이트 했는데요
I had a date last night.
그녀 눈은 아주 환상적인
녹색이었어요, 뿅 갔어요
And this girl has the most impossible
green eyes. Just, BAM.
어깨까지 내려오는 금발에
Shoulder-length blonde hair.
지적이고
Intelligent.
향기도 아주 고왔어요
And she smells so good.
발가락도 예쁘던가?
Cute toes?
네! 이상적이었죠
Oh, ideal.
엄지발가락보다 긴 것이 없었어요
And none longer than the big toe
양쪽 발 모두요
Both feet.
그런데요. 제가 알고 싶은 건
그녀 안에 뭐가 있는가 예요
But you know I need to know
is what is on the inside.
마음속에 뭐가 있는데?
What's in her heart?
아뇨, DNA 구조가 알고 싶어요
No, her DNA.
그녀는 꽤 좋은 상피세포를
가지고 있어요
And, let me tell you, this girl
has got some fine epithelials.
이봐, 자네 정상이 아냐
정말 정신 나간 것 같아
Dude, you're sick.
Man, you have officially lost it.
아뇨, 루이스 빌에 한 남자는
300달러 받고
There's a guy in Louisville,
he charges 300 clams
부인의 속옷에 다른 남자의
DNA가 있는지 검사하죠
to test your spouses' underwear
for foreign DNA.
그 남자가 정상이 아닌 거죠
전 낭만적이라고요
Now that guy is sick.
I'm just a romantic.
같이 커피를 마시며
Whatever happened getting to know
someone over coffee.
서로에 대해 알아가고
관계를 발전시키는 건 뭘까?
Letting the relationship evolve.
낭만적인 건 꽃은 보내는 거지
Romantic is sending flowers,
그녀의 피부 세포를
독점하는 게 아냐
not bogarting her skin cells.
아, 그런 말은 지루해요
Oh, that's boring.
뭐예요? 뭘 찾았죠?
What are you doing?
What've you got?
칼에 찔린 남자한테서
이런 털이 좀 나왔어
Pulled a couple of hairs off
of our male stabbing vic.
알았어요
Okay.
귀여운 것
Baby.
뭔데?
What?
아홉 개의 목숨
Nine lives.
고양이털?
Cat hair?
야~옹
Meow.
케빈 셰퍼드
상체에 찔린 상처가 6군데 있어
Kevin Shepherd six stab
wounds to the upper torso.
등에 한군데, 앞에 다섯 군데
One to the back.
Five to the front.
그 사람 아내는요?
And his wife?
에이미 셰퍼드
목을 오른쪽에서 왼쪽으로 한 번 베였어
Amy Shepherd, one slice
across the neck. Right to left.
왼손잡이 소행이군요
Work of a lefty.
정경맥과 두 경동맥을 끊어버렸어
(정경맥, 경동맥 : 목에 분포된 혈관)
The blade transected the jugular vein
and both carotids.
목이 잘리면 비명을
지르기 어렵죠
Hard to scream when
your throat's been cut.
방어하다 생긴 상처군요
Defense wounds.
이 남자 한번은 저항했어
This guy put up one hell of a fight.
두 개의 칼로 공격당했어
Attacked with two weapons.
두 개요?
두 종류의 찔린 상처가 있어
Two? / Two types of stab wounds.
하나는 길고 날카로운 양날 칼이야
first, a long, sharp, double-edged blade.
예리하게 찔렸어
The blade went in smooth...
피부에 멍을 조금 남겼고
Left little collateral bruising to the skin.
또 하나는 둔한 거야
Weapon number two was blunt.
두 번째 무기는 찔린
부위에 넓은 멍을 냈어
Weapon number two caused extensive
bruising around the points of entry.
무기가 두개면
범인도 2명이겠군요
Two weapons, two attackers.
이봐요, 시 건축 감독관
어디 있어요?
Hi, District engineer?
저기요
Over there.
넥타이 멘 사람이군
Ah, follow the tie.
비 때문인가요?
Is that from the rain?
누군데 그걸 묻는 거요
Depends on who's asking.
숨기는 게 있는 건지 아니면
제가 상대할 가치가 없는 건가요?
Are you hiding something,
or am I not worth your time?
뭐라고요?
Excuse me?
이봐요, 당신, 시 건축 감독관 맞죠?
Well, you are the District Engineer
for the city, right?
이 건물의 안전에
대한 책임이 있죠
You're responsible for
the structural safety of this building.
미안한데요, 성함이 ?
I'm sorry.
I didn't catch your name.
캐서린 윌로우스입니다
라스베가스 과학수사대예요
Catherine Willows.
Las Vegas Crime Lab.
과학수사대요?
예
Crime Lab? / Yeah.
건물이 무너져 3명이
깔려 죽었어요
the building fell down.
Three people were crushed to death.
왜 나무가 젖었죠?
Why is the wood wet?
이 건물은 지붕이 평평해요
물이 새는 게 특별한 건 아니죠
Well it's a flat-roofed structure.
Leaks aren't a uncommon problem.
건식부패의 원인일 수 있겠군요
Could explain the dry rot.
저건 뭐죠?
What am I looking at?
석고보드요
That would be sheetrock.
건식벽이군요
Drywall.
여기 이 층은 어떻게 된 건가요?
But what about this layer right here?
처음 시공할 때는 1/2인치
두께의 석고 보드를 썼는데
When they installed the original drywall
they used half-inch and
나중에 수리할 때는 1/4인치
두께의 석고 보드를 썼어요
when they came back later and repaired it,
they used quarter of an inch.
그 날 1/4인치 보드를
할인판매라도 했나요?
What, was quarter inch
on sale that day?
이봐요, 아가씨
지금 뭘 하자는 지 모르겠소
Look, lady, I don't know what it is...
캐서린이요
Catherine.
미안해요
Sorry.
미안하다고 할 필요 없고요
누구와 얘기하는 지나 알아두세요
Don't say 'sorry.'
Just know who you're talking to.
그들이 두 번째 벽판을 신청하고
발라 붙인 뒤 페인트칠했을 때에는
Once the dry wall's spackled and painted,
차이점이 안 나타났어요
the difference wasn't noticeable.
지금은 차이점이 보이네요
It's noticeable now.
마지막으로 감독을 한
건축 감독관이 누구죠?
Which District Engineer
conducted the last inspection?
시 건축 감독관은 한 명뿐이오
There's only one District Engineer.
그렇담 당신 좀 곤란하게 됐군요
Then it looks bad for you.
자자, 알았어요, 캐서린
Okay, look, Catherine.
보고서를 작성해서 이메일로
당신께 보내드릴게요, 어때요?
Why don't I write up my report and
e-mail it to you? How would that be?
어디서부터 무너지기 시작했죠?
Where's the point of origin of the collapse?
이봐요, 제가 맡은
사건 현장이에요
Look, this is my crime scene.
저 스스로 찾을 수도 있어요
I could find it myself.
하지만 그건 많은 사람들에게
많은 질문을 해야 한다는 뜻이기도 하죠
But that might mean lots of
questions to lots of people.
그러시다면 전문가 견해로는
우리 바로 밑에 있다고 봐요
Well, it's just my expert opinion,
but I'd say right below us.
지하 세탁실이요
In the basement.
The laundry room.
그렇다면 그곳이 제가
가고자하는 곳이네요
Then that's where I want to be.
저, 반장님
Hey Gris.
케빈 셰퍼드는 물리 치료사고요
에이미 셰퍼드는 치과 의사예요
Kevin Shepherd. Chiropractor.
Amy Shepherd. Dentist.
집은 호숫가에 있고
결혼 8년차에 신용도도 좋아요
House in the Lakes. Married eight years.
Perfect credit.
근데 감도 안 잡히네요
You know, I'm lost.
실마리도 전혀 없어요
There's, there's nothing
jumping off the page here.
목격자는 ?
What about the eyewitness?
저스틴 그린
Justine Green,
첫 번째 목격자이자 첫 번째 용의자지만
그는 우리를 기다리며 앉아있었죠
first witness for the suspects but
he hung around, waiting for us.
피투성이인 채로
And he was covered in blood.
그러나 그의 얘기는 일치해요
But his story jibes.
다른 목격자가 그가 심폐소생술을
케빈 셰퍼드에게 한 것을 보았어요
Several witnesses saw him
performing CPR on Kevin Shepherd.
그런데 만약 그 사건이 차량절도
사건이라면 이해가 안 돼요
But, if it was a car-jacking,
I don't get it.
왜 목숨 걸며 싸웠죠?
바퀴 4개와 껍데기뿐인데요
I mean why fight to the death?
It's four wheels and a chassis.
상황이 극으로 치닫게 되면
그건 차가 아니라 재산이 되지
In the heat of the moment,
it's not a car. It's a possession.
그래서 사람들은 그들이 무슨 위험을
안은 지도 모르는 채 싸우게 되지
And people will fight, without
realizing what they're risking.
그렇다면 반장님은 셰퍼드 부부가
SUV 때문에 죽었다고 생각하세요?
So, you are thinking the Shepherds
lost their lives for their SUV?
보편적으로 그렇다는 것이지
셰퍼드 부부 건의 경우에는
I'm seaking in generalities.
Regarding the Shepherds,
나 또한 감이 안 와
자네처럼
I'm in the dark, too.
Just like you.
이봐, 워릭
Hey, Warrick.
그리섬 못 봤나?
Is, ah, Grissom around?
반장 찾나요?
You see him?
우리끼리 얘기지만
난 이 일을 오래했어도
You know between you and me,
as long as I've been on the job
아직도 사체 만지긴 싫어
I still don't like touching dead bodies.
그래서 경감님은
배지를 달고 계시고
Well, that's why you've got the badge,
전 주사기를 들고
있는 거 아니겠습니까
and I've got the syringe.
칼에 찔린 상처
본뜨고 있어요
I'm casting the stab wounds.
본뜬 걸로 범행에 쓰인
무기를 찾을 수 있겠죠
From the molds. We can
identify the murder weapons.
자네 점점 그리섬 닮아 가는군
You're getting more like
Grissom every day, man.
반장에게 전할 말씀 있나요?
Did you want me to give
Grissom a message?
어
Yeah.
순찰차가 셰퍼드의 SUV 찾았어
A patrol car located
the Shepherds' SUV.
자동차는 죽은 부부의
명의로 되어 있어
Car is registered to our dead couple.
자동차를 훔칠 생각이었으면
갖고 있지, 버리지는 않죠
When you carjack a car, you keep the car.
You don't dump it.
장난으로 그러지
않았으면 그렇겠지
Unless you're joyriding.
장난운전 때문에
사람을 죽였을까요?
Who kills for a joyride?
처음은 아닐걸
Wouldn't be the first time.
자네 말고 저 차 만진 사람 있나?
Has anybody else touched this vehicle?
아닙니다, 저 혼자
저 차를 발견했습니다
No, sir. And I'm the one who found it.
비 때문에
Just the rain.
차 밖의 증거들은
손상되었을 거야
The evidence on the outside
of the vehicle would be compromised.
안에는 증거가 있겠지요
Well, maybe there'll be
some evidence on the inside.
한동안 못 느꼈던 것을 느끼네요
Well, I haven't felt that in a while.
그게 뭔데?
What's that?
놀라움이요
The element of surprise.
이 여자 여기서 뭘 했을까?
What's she doing here?
좋은 질문이네요, 그것보다
이 여자는 누구일까요?
Good question.
Better question, who is she?
장갑 끼고 하세요
Ah, put some gloves on.
내참, 자네가 사건 현장을
훼손했다는 게 믿기지 않아
You know, I can't believe
you messed up a crime scene.
문 열자마자 시신이 떨어졌어요
우연이었고, 그냥 진행해야죠
The body fell out when I opened the door.
It happens. We move on.
하루 종일 신경 쓰이겠군
It'll bother you all day.
제시카 홀
73년 8월 5일 생
Jessica Hall. Date of birth, 8/5/73.
휴대전화는 꺼져있어
911에도 안 걸었어
Cell phone power's off.
Didn't call nine one one.
만약 걸었다면 전화를 계속
켜 놓으라고 지시했을 텐데
They would've instructed her
to keep it on.
안전벨트를 안 채웠군요
그래서 그녀가 떨어졌어요
Seatbelt was unbuckled
that's why she fell out.
그래서?
Yeah, so?
그녀는 운전석에 있었어요
근데 그녀가 운전을 했을까요?
She's in the driver's seat,
but was she driving?
아니면 누가 옮겨 놨을까요?
Or could she have been placed in here?
아마 이 여자는 28% 미국인처럼
안전벨트 안 하고 운전했을 거야
Maybe she's like 28 percent of Americans,
she doesn't buckle up.
제가 알기론 정확하게 29%일걸요
I think twenty-nine percent actually.
변사체 발견 보고하겠네
I'll go radio the 419.
알레르기 없죠? 반장님
Hope you're not allergic there, boss.
뭐라고?
고양이 털입니다
What? / Cat hair.
케빈 셰퍼드의 옷에서
나온 털과 비슷해요
Found similar hairs on
Kevin Shepherd's clothing.
에이미 셰퍼드에서는?
How about Amy Shepherd?
아니요, 그녀에겐 없었어요
Nope. No hairs on the wife.
셰퍼드의 SUV
칼에 찔린 상처, 고양이 털
Shepherd's SUV.
Stab wound. Cat hair.
이 여자는 첫 번째 살인 현장과
연관되어 있군. 그런데 어떻게?
She's linked to the first crime scene.
But how?
다른 장소와 다른 시간에
3번째 피해자가 나왔을까
Victim number three.
Wrong place, wrong time.
보지 말아야 할 걸 본 경우겠죠
Saw something she shouldn't.
음, 결국에는
예?
Well, finally. / What?
누군가가 이론을 제시했잖아
Someone has a theory.
이봐요, 제 밑엔 이런 일을 위해
훈련받은 사람들이 있어요
Look, I got guys
who are trained to do this.
그들을 불러 하면 안돼요?
Why don't you let me crawl.
당신이 그 곳에 들어가면
그 멋진 복장이 더러워질걸요
You're gonna go in there and
you get that snappy little jumpsuit dirty.
악의 없는 말입니다만,
그들은 당신 밑에서 일하잖아요
No offense, but they work for you.
그게 어때서요?
Well, so what?
희생자 가족들은 사인을
알 권리가 있어요
Well, so the victims' family
deserves answers.
누군가는 책임을 져야겠죠
Somebody's responsible.
내참, 난 잘못한 것 없어요
Hey, I didn't do anything wrong.
예, 물론 고의적인 것은 아니겠지요
하지만 ...
Well, maybe not intentionally. But...
만약 배가 가라앉는다면
if a ship sinks,
누수를 확인했던 마지막
사람의 부주의 때문이죠
the last person who checked
for leaks is negligent.
아직 결혼 안 했죠, 맞죠?
You're not married, are you?
이혼했군요
Divorced.
당신이 보는 건
저도 봅니다
What you see, I'll see.
내 분명히 말하는데
이건 나쁜 생각이요
But I just want to go on record,
this is a bad idea.
정보 고마워요
Thanks for your input.
서로 직통으로 연결됐어요
We're on a hot feed.
갑니다
I'm going in.
전 여기 있죠
I'll be right here.
캐서린
Catherine.
정말 들어갈 거야?
You sure you want to do this?
왜 모든 사람이 제가
진짜 들어갈 거냐고 묻죠?
Why is everybody asking me
if I want to do my job?
왜냐면 자네가 걱정돼서
Because we care.
그리고
And
시장님께서 도시 재개발에 대한
계획을 발표하셨어
The Mayor ran on a platform
of urban renewal.
악덕 임대인들을 몰아내고
Clean out the slumlords,
시에서 쾌적한 아파트를
지어 저렴하게 공급하겠다는 거야
create habitable low cost housing
maintained by the city.
만약에 작은 문제라도 발견된다면
You find so much as a scratch
on an aspirin in there,
그 화살이 누구에게
돌아올지 잘 알거야
you know who it's going to come back to.
전 제 할일만 할겁니다
실례해요
I know I have a job to do.
Excuse me.
안녕하세요, 박사님
Hey, Doc,
형광투시경으로 뭐 하세요?
what's with the fluoroscope?
사체를 들여왔을 때
When we brought the body into the lab,
금속탐지기가 울렸어
she set off the meta detector.
주머닌 확인했어요?
Did you check in her pockets?
주머니엔 아무것도 없었어
Nothing in the pockets.
안쪽에 핀이나 판 같은
금속물질 같은 것 없었나요?
What about a pin or plate.
Anything metallic on the inside?
나도 그 생각을 했어
하지만 아무 것도 못 찾았어
I had the same thought,
but that's not what we found.
데이빗, 시신 올려봐
David, take her down.
알겠습니다
Yes, sir.
사인은 간 파열이야
Cause of death,
laceration of the liver.
과다 출혈이군요
Exsanguination.
간이 찔렸을 때
응급처치 안 하면
Once you nick the liver,
it's almost impossible to stop the bleeding
출혈을 막기는 거의 불가능하지
without immediate medical intervention.
데이빗
Woah, David,
12번 갈비뼈를 다시 보여줘
go back up to the 12th rib, please.
나도 그걸 보려 했어
I was just getting to that.
범인이 기념품을 남겼군요
Our killer leave us a souvenir.
저게 뭐죠?
What is that?
웨이터에게 뭘 주지?
What do you leave your waiter?
팁, 칼끝이군요
A tip. Of a knife.
저거 빨리 볼 수 있겠죠?
How soon could we
get that out of the body?
지하에 거의 다 왔나요?
Am I almost at ground zero?
거의 다 왔어요
한 3미터 정도 더 가면 ...
Almost. About ten more feet,..
세탁실이 보일 겁니다
you should see the laundry room.
천장높이도 좀 높을 거예요
You should have be more headroom, too.
빨대 속을 기어가는 것 같군요
I feel like I'm crawling through a straw.
예쁜데
Sweet.
뭐예요?
What? What is it?
이거 안 보여요?
Are you getting this?
뭡니까? 바퀴벌레요?
What is that, a roach?
전 곤충학자가 아니지만
잘 아는 사람 한 명 있어요
I'm not an entomologist,
but I know one.
그 사람이 말해 줄 거예요
He can tell us.
제 생각엔 이 건물
안전할 줄 알았는데요
I thought this building was secure.
안전해요, 계속가요
It is secure. Just hang on.
매일 있는 비행입니다
F-16 같군요
Daily sorties. I think that was an F-16.
넬리스 공군 기지
Nellis Air Force Base.
남쪽으로 1마일 정도 가면 있죠
About a mile south of here.
제가 더 알아야 할 사항이 있나요?
Anything else I should be aware of?
없어요
You're in the clear.
알았어요
Okay.
됐어요, 세탁실에 왔어요
Okay, I'm in the laundry room,
잔해들이네요
what's left of it.
보면서 말해 줄 수 있나요?
You wanna talk me through this.
위를 봐요
아마 들보를 볼 수 있을 거요
Okay. Look up. You should be
able to see the beam now
- 발견했어요
- 좋아요
Got it. / Alright
지지기둥은 들보와 이어지면서
connected to the beam
콘크리트 최하부에 수직으로
이어져 있을 거예요
running vertically into the concrete foundation,
are the support columns.
요즘은 검사가 깐깐해서
지지기둥을 강철로 만들지만
Now, in a perfect world,
they should be steel. But...
건물의 건축년도를 고려하면
아마 나무로 되어 있을 거요
given the age of this building,
they might be wood.
예, 나무예요, 맞네요
Yeah, it's wood, all right.
그리고 누군가가 기둥에
해머 질 한 것 같아 보이네요
And it looks like somebody
took a sledgehammer to it.
그래 당신들이 정말
이걸 시체에서 꺼냈단 말이요
So you really pulled this
out of a corpse?
예, 당신을 위해 씻었어요
Yeah, but I cleaned it for you.
그 칼의 종류를
알았으면 하는데요
We need to know the make of the knife.
이건 칼날이 아니요
Well, it's not a knife.
날 끝이 양날이고 양날 끝의
형태가 아래로 향하는 모양이니
The tip's double-edged. Bevels
on both sides. Downward slope.
이건 단도에서 떨어졌고
This came from a dagger.
스테인레스강이나 탄소강
중 하나겠네요
Which means it's either Carbon steel
or Stainless steel.
당신들이 생각하는 것보다
이런 질문 많이 받아요
I get asked this question
more than you think.
레몬주스의 산이 탄소강에는 반응하지만
스테인레스강에는 반응 안 하죠
The acid in the lemon juice should react
with carbon steel, but not stainless steel.
경찰이 이런 것을 어떻게 다 알죠?
How's a cop know all this?
이 분은 경찰이고 전 과학자죠
He's the cop. I'm the scientist.
경찰다운 질문 하나 하죠
뭘 찾는 겁니까?
I got a cop question.
What are we looking for here?
검은 흔적이요
Dark spots.
탄소강이군요
다음은?
Carbon Steel. What's next?
길이죠
Length.
칼 끝부분이 1인치가
넘는 단도는 드물죠
Daggers are rarely more than
an inch at the base.
칼끝이 있으니
나머지를 찾을 수 있죠
We got the tip,
so we can fill in the rest.
기초 기하학이죠
It's basic geometry.
12센티군
Five inches.
길이가 12센티에 탄소강 단도라
이게 당신들이 찾는 거요
Top rows, five-inch daggers. Carbon steel.
This is the one you want.
24달러 99센트고
신용카드는 안 받소
Twenty-four, ninety-nine.
We don't take credit cards.
예
Yeah.
셰퍼드 부인에 대해서는 잠시 접어두세요
목 베인 상처를 맞출 수가 없었거든요
Forget Shepherd's wife.
I can't match the slice marks.
전부 찔린 상처에서 관한 거라서요
케빈 셰퍼드에 대해 집중했죠
It's all about these stab wounds.
So I consentrated on Kevin Shepherd.
정말 잘했어, 워릭
알다시피 주조도 예술이야
This is a nice job Warrick.
You know casting is an art.
예술가가 작업하는 동안
And while the artist was at work,
경감님과 저는
제시카 홀의 살해 도구를
Brass and I identified
Jessica Halls murder weapon
그녀의 갈비뼈에서 발견한
칼날 끝을 통해 찾았어요
from the tip we found
lodged in her ribs.
단검이고 종류는
후가시 502형이에요
It's a dagger.
Fugasi Model 502.
멋진데
Cool.
결국 제시카 홀에게
사용된 무기를 찾아냈군
Okay, so now we know the type of
dagger used on Jessica Hall.
이게 케빈 셰퍼드에게도
사용되었을까?
Was it also used on Kevin Shepherd?
케빈의 사체에서 날카롭게
찔린 모든 부분을 측정했는데
Well, I measured all the sharp points
of entry on Kevin's body.
그것들은 모두 일치했어요
같은 무기에 의해 생긴 겁니다
They're all indentical. They're all
made by the same murder weapon.
그렇다면 만약 이 단검이
네가 만든 틀과 같다면
So if this dagger matches your mold.
날카롭게 찔린 상처에
대한 것은 찾아냈군
Okay, we just put the sharp wounds to bed.
첫 번째 범행도구는 확인했으니
Identified murder weapon number one.
이제 두 번째 범행도구를
확인해야지
Now we just need the second weapon...
이 두 상처를 찌른 칼은
끝이 무딘 것 맞지?
Points of impact on these two
were blunt. Right?
응, 누가 무딘 칼로
사람을 찌르지?
Who stabs somebody
with a blunt instrument?
새라, 시신에서 나온 단검
끝부분 지금 가지고 있어?
Sara, you still have the dagger tip
from the body. / Yeah.
예
그리고 미확인 범행도구
주조물 있지?
And you have the cast of
the unidentified murder weapon?
예
Yeah.
단검은 다이아몬드가 아냐
영원히 그 상태로 있지 않지
A dagger is not a diamond,
it doesn't last forever.
무기가 2개가 아니었군
We don't have two weapons.
결국 케빈에게 시작한 뒤
그 다음 제시카에게 갔고
So he started with Kevin.
and then he went after Jessica.
칼끝이 부러졌고
And then the tip broke off.
다시 케빈을 마무리했네요
And then he went back to Kevin
and finished the job.
무기가 하나니
범인도 한 명이야
One weapon. One killer.
애노비드 파우더 포스트 딱정벌레군
An Anobiid Powder Post Beetle.
매우 좋은 종이야
Very nice specimen.
반장님을 좋아하나봐요
He likes you, too.
이 곤충에 대해 말씀해주세요
Now, tell me about him.
그 건물이 무너졌지?
Your building collapsed.
제게 맡겼으니
알고 계시지 않았나요
You assigned me the case.
You already know that.
이 친구가 증명해 줄 거야
Well, this little guy confirms it.
이 종의 딱정벌레들은
연한 나무를 먹고 살지
This species of beetle
eats softwood.
건물에 대해 말해 주겠어?
Tell me about the building.
골격이 미송이었어요
The frame's made of Douglas Fir.
맛있었겠군
A delicacy.
딱정벌레 말고 다른 것도 찾았어요
I did find more than a bug.
건식부패와 의심스러운 수리과정
신경과민의 기사
Dry rot, questionable repairs,
a jittery engineer.
그리고 이것 좀 봐요
And check this out.
딱정벌레는 아냐
이 손상은 고의적인 거야
Forget the beetle,
this damage was intentional.
사람(Homo sapiens)의 짓이군
You're looking for a Homo sapiens.
알아요, 새로운 이름을 붙인다면
가정 파괴범(home wrecker)이겠죠
I know.
Gives new meaning to "home wrecker."
캐서린, 내가 자네한테
이 일을 맡긴 이유가 있어
Catherine, there's a reason
I assigned you this case.
자넨 죽은 사람이나 산 사람 모두에게
좋은 사람이기 때문이지
You're good with people,
both the dead and the living.
다른 말로 해석하면 골치 아픈
정치문제를 다뤄야 한다는 것이지요
Translation, we're opening
a political can of worms.
시장과 관련 있는 일이고
선거는 다가오고 있고
The Mayor's involved and
election's around the corner.
제게 좀 더 일찍 힌트를
줄 수 있었을 텐데요
You could have clued me
in a little earlier.
이거 내가 가져도 되겠나?
Can I keep him?
안 되죠
증거잖아요
Sorry. It's evidence.
먹이 주는 것 잊지 마
Don't forget to feed him.
예, 나무요
I know wood.
그렇지
Oh yeah.
변속기에서 지문 3개 찾았어
선명한데
I got three prints on this gear shift.
And they are beauties.
땀이 많이 나면 지문도 잘 남지
Sweaty palms
make for the best prints.
검시관이 제시카 홀의
지문 사진 10장을 보냈어
The Coroner just sent over a ten card
of Jessica Hall's fingerprints.
신참 배달원이 된 것 같군
Evidently I am the new delivery boy.
내가 생각하고 있는 것을 하고 있나?
Are you doing
what I think you're doing?
우리가 찾고 있는 것을 찾았다면
답은 "예"겠죠
If we find what we're looking for,
yes, the answer is yes.
지문들 좀 볼 수 있을까?
Can I see those prints.
이미지 인쇄중이야
Images are printing.
고마워
Thanks.
지문판독시스템도 필요 없겠어
육안으로도 확인되요
No need for AFIS.
We got a visual match.
모든 지문이 3번째 희생자 지문이에요
All three prints belong to
victim number three.
그렇다면 제시카 홀이
SUV를 운전한 마지막 사람이겠군
So Jessica Hall was the last person
to drive the Shepherds' SUV.
이게 뭘 의미하죠?
What does that give us?
우리가 아는 건 그녀가
사건현장에서 찔렸다는 거죠
We know she was stabbed
at the crime scene.
하지만 그 다음에는 뭐죠?
그녀 혼자 병원에 갔나요?
But then what?
Was she driving herself to the hospital?
협박 받았을까요?
Was she under duress?
다 아니야
None of the above.
반장님 제 이론 아시죠?
그래
Hey Grissom, you know
that theory I had? / Yeah.
그것을 좀 바꾸고 싶은데요
I'd like to revise it.
새 증거가 나올 때마다 과학자는
이론을 재검토해야겠지, 닉
It's a scientist right to re-examine your theory
with each new piece of evidence, Nick.
제 증거는 증거물 검토실에 있어요
My evidence is in the layout room.
케빈 셰퍼드의 상처는
모두 상체에 있었죠
All the wounds sustained by
Kevin Shepherd were to his torso.
자, 이걸 보세요
Now, look at this.
케빈 셰퍼드 신발의
왼쪽 안으로 피가 흘렀어요
Blood flow on the left instep
of Kevin Shepherd's shoe.
다행히도 비에
씻기지 않았어요
Lucky for us,
the rain missed that.
즉사한 경우가 아니면
When death is not immediate,
피해자는 본능적으로
태아의 모습처럼 웅크리지
a victim instinctively
curls up in the fetal position.
그래서 비에 씻기지 않았어
Which may have protected this
from the rain.
그래서 핏자국이 남았군요
That's why the blood pattern
was preserved.
이 피가 피해자의
거라고 보이지만
You expect blood on victims,
다시 생각해보면
but let's ask the question
피살자의 일반적인 행동으로 볼 때
피가 여기까지 묻어날까?
Could the normal action and behavior
of our victim have put his blood there?
피살자는 등을 대고 누워 있고
Victim was lying on his back.
상처는 상체에만 있으니
Wounds above the waist.
이건 케빈의 피가 아니겠네요
It's not Kevin's blood.
누가 또 피를 흘렸죠?
Who else had a flowing wound?
에이미 셰퍼드는
너무 멀리 있었지만
Amy Shepherd was too far away.
제시카 홀은 살아
피를 흘리고 있었죠
But Jessica Hall
was alive and bleeding.
좋아, 그렇다면 어떻게
제시카 피가 그의 신발에 묻었지?
Okay. How did her blood
get on his shoe?
중력이죠
Gravity.
워릭, 바닥에 등 대고 누워줄래
Warrick, please,
on the floor, on your back.
이봐, 왜 날마다
날 눕히려고 하지?
Man, you're always
trying to put me down.
새라, 너는 제시카야
Sara, you're Jessica.
오라고, 어서
Come on now.
알았어
Okay.
준비됐어
Alright.
좋아, 지금 나는 복부에
피를 흘리고 있어
Alright, I'm bleeding from my abdomen.
이렇게 서 있으면 많은 피를
워릭에게 못 묻힐 거예요
Standing here, I'm not going to
get that much blood on Warrick.
더 가까이 가봐
Get closer.
밟지 않으면 더
나갈 수가 없어요
Well, I can't without stepping on him.
무릎을 꿇으면 가능해
You can if you kneel down.
그녀가 왜 그렇게 했죠?
Why would she do that?
아마 케빈을 돕거나
저항을 막았겠지
Possibly to help or to hinder.
전 케빈의 저항을
막았다고 봐요
I say hinder.
다리를 잡아!
Grab his legs.
그녀는 그 곳에 있었어요
She was in on it.
그녀는 범인이 케빈을 찌르는
동안 케빈을 잡고 있었어요
She held him down,
while someone else stabbed him.
그녀의 상처 위치로 보아
By the positioning of her wound,
상처는 실수로 찔린 것 같아요
I'd say it looked like
stabbing was an accident.
상처 자국이
난잡하고 부정확해요
Stabbings are messy and inexact.
그렇다면 3번 피해자는
2번 용의자이겠네요
So victim number three
becomes suspect number two.
닉, 제시카 아파트
수색영장 신청해
Nick, get a warrant for
Jessica Hall's apartment.
2번 용의자가 1번 용의자를
찾을 수 있게 해 주는지 보자고
We'll see if suspect number two
leads us to suspect number one.
그리고 점수판도 가져오고
And bring a scorecard with you.
좀 도와드릴까요?
Can I give you a hand with that?
아뇨
Nope.
여긴 어떻게 들어왔죠?
How'd you get in here?
시청 공무원 신분증을 들이밀고
웃어주니까 되던데요
Well I flashed my city I.D.
And, uh, my smile.
뭘 찾고 있죠?
What are we looking for?
건물을 붕괴시킨
이런저런 원인을요
A lot of factors
contributed to the collapse.
전 사람과 연관된 것에 대해
초점을 맞추고 있어요
I'm focusing on the human element.
만약 최근 이 기둥에 해머 질을 했다면
변색된 흔적이 있을 거예요
Now if a sledgehammer was taken to this column
recently, there'd be evidence of discoloration.
손상된 부근이 좀 밝겠죠
The damaged part would be lighter.
제가 봐도 될까요?
May I?
손 치워주세요
알았어요, 미안해요
Hands off. / Oh, Right sorry.
없어요, 변색되지 않았어요
No. No discoloration.
그 이유를 알고 싶어요?
Would you like to know why?
예
Sure.
5년 전, 이 아파트에 대한 민원이
끊이지 않았죠
Five years ago, this building
was apartment Vietnam.
건물 시설들은 기준미달이었고
The facility was sub-standard.
시에서는 신경도 안 썼죠
세입자들은 농성을 했고
The city turned it's back.
The tenants revolted.
204호에 사는 블레이크
네퍼슨이란 사람이
Blake Neferson, apartment 204,
그 기둥에 해머 질을 했어요
took a sledgehammer to that column.
공부(公簿)예요
네퍼슨은 체포되었죠
It's public record.
He was arrested.
공부(公簿)라?
Public record?
그런데 검사일지에는
왜 이 손상은 빠져있죠?
And you failed to indicate the damage
in your inspection reports?
신경 쓸 만큼의
손상은 아니었어요
There wasn't enough damage
to cause concern.
깔려 죽은 고인들께
그 얘길 해 보시죠
Tell that to the women
who were crushed to death.
케빈 셰퍼드의 신발에 있는 피가
제시카의 피와 일치한다고 하던데요
I heard the lab matched the blood on
Kevin Shepherd's shoe to Jessica.
제 이론이 점점 맞아들고 있어요
My theory's getting better and better.
서두르지 말게, 니콜라스(닉)
Not so fast, Nicholas.
조사결과 셰퍼드가 안드레에서
제시카와 통화한 내용이 나왔어
P.D. traced a phone call Shepherd made
to Jessica from Andre's Restaurant.
자신을 죽이려는 걸 도운 여자에게
전화는 왜 했을까요?
What's he doing calling the woman
who helped kill him?
그건 자네 생각이지
It's you're theory, pal.
제시카 양은 메모를
많이 하는 사람이군
Our little Jessica was a prolific note-taker
"오늘은 착한 사람이 되자"
"Be a good person today."
응, 맞아
너무 많은 사람을 죽이진 말아야지
Yeah, right.
Try not to kill too many people.
냉수기 배달 취소하기
Cancel water cooler delivery.
여자 친구들끼리
몰래 외출 계획 잡기
Plan girls' night out.
베란다 전구 구매할 것
Light bulbs for porch.
아주 중요한 증거물 하날
찾은 것 같아요
I think I found a key piece of evidence.
우리가 찾던 빨강머리죠
The redhead we've been looking for.
붉은 털은 제시카에게 있었고
그녀는 집고양이를 키우고 있지
Red hairs on Jessica.
She owns a Tabby Cat.
그리고 셰퍼드에게서도
붉은 털이 나왔지
Red hairs on Shepherd.
셰퍼드가 그의 부인이
없이 여기 있었겠네요
Chances are, Sheppard was here
without his wife.
그래, 제시카와 셰퍼드의
통화내역을 확인해 볼게
Yeah, I'm gonna run Jessica's
cell phone records. And Shepherd's.
그 둘 사이에 무슨 일이
있는지 알 수 있겠지
Whatever was going on between the two,
we'll find out.
자넨 여기 있게나
Stay here, fella.
에이첵스에 접속하려면
아이콘을 더블클릭 할 것
To access Achex.
Double click icon.
사용자 이름은 Jessica
비밀번호는 Money
Username: Jessica.
Password: money.
해봐
예
- Try it.
- Yeah.
에이첵스, 인터넷뱅킹
Achex.
Personal on-line banking.
예금, 수표, 송금 등
모든 걸 할 수 있네요
Deposits, checking, money transfers,
everything's under the sun.
됐어요, 접속했어요
Okay, I'm in.
뷰몬트 백화점에서 매주
500달러씩 입금되었네요
Direct deposit from Beaumont's
Department Store : $500 dollars a week.
아마 그녀의 주급 같아요
Probably her weekly paycheck.
그러다가 35,000달러가
하루에 입금되었다고?
And then a $35,000 day.
복권 당첨이라도 됐을까요?
She win the lottery?
한달에 2,000달러 버는 사람이
어떻게 하루에 35,000달러를
How's a girl who makes two thousand
dollars a month, pull in $35,000,
한 번에 송금되었을까?
only to give it away on the same day?
누구에게 줬는지 확인해 볼게요
Let's see who she gave it to.
아직 안 나왔군
It hasn't posted yet.
운이 없네요
No luck.
조금 뒤로 가봐
Go back a little.
누구에게 받았는지는 알았군
케빈 셰퍼드군
Well, we know who she got it from,
Kevin Shepherd.
잠깐만요
Wait a minute.
셰퍼드가 제시카에게 자신과 아내를
죽여 달라고 돈을 보냈을까요?
Shepherd paid Jessica
to murder him and his wife?
그럴 수 있고, 아닐 수도 있지
Maybe. Maybe not.
이거만 가지고 뭐라 할 수 없겠어, 닉
게다가 모든 사람은 죽어버렸잖아
I can't speak for the evidence, Nick.
And everybody else is dead.
용의자 아파트에서 가져온 거예요
I took this from our suspect's apartment.
부부가 차량도난 당한 사건이죠
그 사건에 대해 들었어요
Husband and wife. Carjacking.
I heard about the case.
친구와 종종 안드레 식당에서
식사하는데, 오싹하네요
My friend and I eat at Andre's. Creepy.
예약을 취소할 것까지는 없어요
Don't cancel your next reservation.
차량도난사건은 아니에요
It wasn't a carjacking.
종이가 새 거네
몇 장밖에 안 썼네요
It's a fresh pad.
Only a couple pages missing.
없어진 종이에 뭘 썼는지
한번 볼까
Let's see what she wrote
on those missing pages.
세탁비 25센트
범죄와 상관없고
Quarters for laundry.
Nothing incriminating.
주차위반 벌금 내기
오후 9시 안드레 식당
Pay parking ticket.
Andre's at 9 P.M. Whoa.
오후 9시 안드레 식당
녹색 SUV
Andre's, nine P.M. Green SUV.
6번가 모퉁이
일요일 오전 8시 K의 사무실
Corner of Sixth.
Sunday, K's office, eight a.m.
이건 살인계획서잖아
This is a blueprint for murder.
K가 케빈의 약자라고 하면
Assuming "K" is Kevin
이들은 살인한지 3일 후에
만나기로 되어 있었어요
they were planning to meet
three days after he was murdered.
그는 제시카에게 35,000달러를 줬어
He paid Jessica thirty-five thousand dollars.
케빈은 제시카에게 식당을
나갈 때 전화했어
He called her as he was leaving the restaurant.
케빈은 원래 죽지
않기로 되어있어
He wasn't supposed to die.
제시카도 마찬가지예요
No either was Jessica.
케빈 셰퍼드는 아내 살인을
청부했지만 뭔가 잘못되었어
Kevin Shepherd took a hit on his wife
and something went wrong.
증거도 있는 것 같아
And we may have the proof.
여기, 케빈 셰퍼드의 살인계획서와
안드레 식당 신용카드 영수증이 있어요
Here, we got your blueprint on Kevin Shepherd's
credit card receipt from Andreas.
좋아요, 일반적으로 서명이
많은 힌트는 못 주지만요
Okay, now normally, a signature
wouldn't give us much.
영수증의 K를 보시고
이제 "K's office"의 K를 보세요
But look at the K on the receipt.
Now look at the K in Kay's office.
또 "SUV"와 "Sunday"의 S를 보시고
이제 "Shepherd"의 S를 보세요
Also look at the "S" in SUV and sunday,
now look at the "S" in Shepherd.
양쪽의 모든 글자가 일치해요
그가 이 두 개의 글을 모두 썼어요
Both letters are identical.
He wrote both these documents.
셰퍼드가 자신의 아내를
살인할 계획을 짠 게 확실하군
Confirms Shepherd planned
the murder of his wife.
저도 동감이에요
근데 왜 죽었죠?
I'm with you.
But why'd he end up dead?
불선업(不善業)이야
Bad karma?
제시카와 셰퍼드는
Jessica and this Shepherd guy
2년 전부터 매일
전화 연락을 했어
have been phoning each other day
and night for the past two years.
무슨 뜻인 것 같아?
What does that tell you?
그들 사이가 매우
좋다는 거겠죠
They had a very healthy relationship.
부인 에이미 몰래
바람을 피웠군요
He was cheating on his wife, Amy.
더 있어
사건 당일 밤 ...
And there's more. On the night of the murder...
제시카는 셰퍼드와 통화한 뒤
after Jessica got off the phone with Sheperd,
다른 사람에게 전화 걸었어
she made a call.
누구에게요?
To who?
반장님이 뭘 찾아야
하는지 말씀 안하셨지?
Grissom didn't say what we
should be looking for, huh?
응, 그냥 옷을
확인하라고만 하셨어
No. Just said 'Check his clothes.'
건조실은 말이야
Drying Room!
8년 동안 이 일을 했지만
여기만 오면 소름이 돋아
Six years on the job
and it still freaks me out in here.
평화롭기만 한데 그래?
- I think it's peaceful.
- Yeah.
찾았다
저스틴 그린
Here we go. Justin Green.
목격자야
The eyewitness.
그가 용의자인가?
언제부터?
He's a suspect?
When did that happen?
비 때문에 망가진 또 다른 것이군
저스틴 재킷에 피의 모양 말이야
Here's another thing the rain ruined.
Blood patterns on Justin's jacket.
티셔츠는 아니지
Not the t-shirt.
워릭, 이거 봐!
Warrick!
이게 뭐같이 보여?
What does that look like to you?
손바닥 자국 같군
That looks like a hand print.
오른 손인가?
Right hand.
저스틴의 손?
Justin's?
손목은 그렇게 꺾이질 않아
Wrist doesn't bend that way.
그럼 저스틴의 손은 아니겠군
So, it's not Justin's.
제시카의 손은 어디
있었는지 알지
We know where Jessica's hands were.
케빈의 발을 잡고 있었지
Holding down Kevin's feet.
에이미 셰퍼드는 즉사했어
And Amy Shepherd died instantly.
그러면 누구의 손이지?
So whose hand print is that?
케빈 셰퍼드의 손이지
Kevin Shepherd's.
케빈 셰퍼드가 방어할 때 생긴
상처를 투명하게 찍은 거야
This is the transparency of
Kevin Shepherd's defense wounds.
상처가 정확히 저스틴의 셔츠에
있는 손바닥 자국과 일치하지
They fit perfectly with the hand print
on Justin's shirt.
저스틴은 심폐소생술을
했다고 했잖아요
Justin's story was that
he performed CPR on Kevin Sheperd.
그랬지, 하지만 케빈이
저스틴의 셔츠를 붙잡고 있었다면
Yeah, but Kevin grabbed Justin's shirt.
케빈은 그 때까지 숨을 쉬고
있었다는 얘기지
So that means
he was still breathing.
케빈에겐 심폐소생술이
필요 없다는 뜻이겠죠
Which means he didn't need CPR.
단도가 저스틴 그린의
손에 있다고 생각해 봐
We just put the dagger
in Justin Green's hand.
이런, 저스틴의 거짓말에
그냥 넘어가 버렸네요
Damn it. Justin sold me a lie
and I bought it.
뭘 하시는 거요?
What are you doing?
당신이 건물붕괴 사건에 책임이
없다는 걸 증명하고 있죠
Proving that you're not responsible
for what happened to that building.
점점 당신이 좋아지는데요
I'm growing on you, aren't I?
손상된 기둥이 부러졌어요
The damaged support column buckled.
왜 일까요?
Why?
건물의 하중이 벽을 지탱하던
이음새에 골고루 가지 않았죠
The weight of the building wasn't evenly
distributed out to the load-bearing walls by the joists.
그렇죠, 이제 호흡이
좀 맞네요
Good. We're on the same page.
저 탱크에 마룻바닥
연결 부분을 넣었어요
Now, I put a section of the floor assembly
in the tank.
그리고 제 딸아이의
고무공을 한 스무 개 정도 넣었어요
I added a dozen of
my daughter's rubberballs.
서브 우퍼 두 개를 달았고요
Two sub-woofers.
그 전부를 진동절연장치
위에 올려놨지요
And put the whole thing
on vibration isolators.
대단한데요
Exactly.
왜냐면, 소음진동이 건물붕괴의
근본적인 원인이라고 보거든요
Because I suspect sound vibrations may be
the ultimate cause of the collapse.
당신 베토벤이 건물을
무너뜨렸다고 주장하는 거요?
Are you saying Beethoven
brought down the building?
아뇨, 아마 F-16이 아니면
No, but, uh, maybe, the F-16s...
넬리스 공군기지에서 뜬
그 이외의 기종이겠죠
and whatever else they're
flying out of Nellis Air Force Base.
이제 진동을 최대화하기 위해
전축의 소리를 높이겠어요
Now, I've ramped up the decibels on the stereo
to maximize the vibrations.
지금 뭐하는 거요
Now you lost me.
공 튀는 것 봐요
Watch the bouncing balls.
못이 돌아가죠
나사처럼요
The nails are rotated. Like screws.
오른쪽으로 돌면 죄여지고
왼쪽으로 돌면 풀리죠
Righty, tighty lefty, loosey.
물론이죠, 못이 헐거워져
연결부위에서 빠졌군요
Of course, loose nails.
Bounce in the joists.
50년 동안 비행한
것을 곱해본다면
Now multiply that by
fifty years of fly-bys.
당신의 요점은 ...
So you're pointing that...
그래서 당신은 공군기지
때문에 생긴 거라 보나요?
So you're pointing the finger
at the Air Force?
아니요, 한 손가락으로
뭘 가리키면
No. When you point one finger,
나머지 네 손가락은
자기한테로 향하죠
there are always gonna be four pointing back at you.
딱정벌레, 기물 손상 행위
건식부패(썩은 나무)
Beetles, sabotage, dry rot...
그리고 시간이죠
and time.
이제 제가 혐의에서
벗어났나요?
Am I off the hook?
예
Yes.
더 할 말 있어요?
Anything you want to say to me?
사실은 ... 있어요
As a matter of fact, yes.
처음부터 날 용의자로 안 봤다면
이렇게 애 먹으며 고생 안했을 거요
you could've saved yourself a lot of trouble
by not making me a suspect in the first place.
천만의 말씀
You're welcome.
문서 제출하라는
법원명령을 받았어
Okay, Jim got us a court order
for production of documents.
왼쪽은 케빈 셰퍼드
On the left, the phone records of Kevin Shepherd,
에이미 셰퍼드, 제시카 홀 그리고
저스틴 그린의 통화 내역이고
Amy Shepherd,
Jessica Hall and Justin Green.
오른쪽은 그들의
은행거래내역이야
On the right,
their banking records.
수요일 10시 2분
Wednesday, 10:02,
케빈은 정부인 제시카에게
35,000달러를 송금했죠
Kevin transferred $35,000
to his mistress Jessica.
수요일 오후 2시 16분
Wednesday 2:16 P.M.
제시카는 그 돈을 다시 출금해서
Jessica transferred the money
out of her account.
저스틴 그린에게 송금을 했다?
To Justin Green?
예
Yes.
35,000달러가 입금되었어요
Deposit for $35,000.
만약 그냥 청부 살해할거라면
Well, if it was a straight-on hit for hire,
제시카는 범죄현장에서
피할 수 있었을지 몰라
Jessica would've steered clear
of the crime scene.
그렇지 않았을 거예요
Maybe not.
1997년 제시카와 저스틴은
공동 계좌를 썼고
In 1997, Jessica and Justin
had a joint account.
성도 같이 썼고요
And they shared the same last name.
음, 의왼데
Whew, curve ball.
결국 제시카는 그녀의 남자친구 부인을
살해하기 위해 전 남편을 고용한 거예요
So Jessica hired her ex-husband
to kill her boyfriend's wife?
모두 얽혀있군
All in the family.
더 중요한 얘기가 있어요
미안해, 닉
I can trump that. Sorry, Nick.
목요일 오전 11시 9분
Thursday. 11:09 a.m.
70,000달러가 저스틴 그린의
계좌에 들어왔어요
$70,000 dollars was transfered
into Justin Green's account.
누구에게서?
From?
제시카도 케빈도 아냐
Not Jessica. Not Kevin.
에이미만 남았군
Only one left is Amy.
예, 맞아요
Yes, that's affirmative.
수요일 오후 3시 저스틴이
에이미 셰퍼드에게 전화를 걸었어요
Wednesday. Three p.m.
Justin called Amy Shepherd.
음, 어떤 대화가 오갔는지
짐작이 되는군
Oh, I bet I can tell you that conversation.
내가 그 말을 정말
믿을 거라 생각해요?
Do you really expect me to believe that?
그래야죠, 이보쇼
당신 남편 바람 피웠어요
Yeah. Look!
You gotta know about the affair.
댁의 남편 은행
계좌를 확인 해봐요
Check his bank account.
35,000달러가 나갔을 겁니다
He paid out thirty-five.
복수하고 싶지 않소?
Want to counter?
그녀는 상상도 못했겠지요
그래서 그녀는 두 배를 줬어요
Amy Shepherd does the unthinkable.
She doubles it.
10만 달러 이상을 벌수 있는데
왜 한 명만 죽이겠어?
Why kill one, when you can take out both
and collect over a hundred grand?
수지맞는 장사군
Makes financial sense.
그리고 저스틴은 보험을 타내려고
And Justin secures the double-cross
with an insurance policy
그를 고용한 사람을 다 죽인 거지
...he eliminates the person
who hired him.
제시카는 사고로 찔린 게 아냐
Jessica wasn't stabbed by accident.
She was a loose end.
제시카가 당한 건
이유를 모르겠어
8년째네요
People said it wouldn't last.
사람들은 우리가 오래가지
못할 것이라 했지
결혼기념일 축하해, 여보
Happy Anniversay, baby.
결혼기념일 축하해
이봐요, 끝났어요
It's over, man.
끝났어요
It's over.
어서 헤어지고
911 불러요
Look, you better split.
Go call 911.
뭐하는 짓이야?
What are you doing?
닥쳐, 이 걸레야!
Shut up, you slut.
저 여잔 내 마누라가 될 사람이야
넌 그녀를 절대 가질 수 없어
She's always gonna be my wife.
You're never gonna have her.
꺼져!
Get away from me.
구급차 불러요
Call an ambulance!
제시카는 차를 타고 가버렸지
Jessica took the car.
그러고 자넨 희생자를 돕는
척하면서 사람들 눈을 속였지
And you hid in plain sight,
offering aid to the victims.
보통 살인 청부하는 이유는
Normally when they pay
to have someone killed,
they do it so they're not
connected to the crime
그 범행에 직접 관여하지
않기 위해서 그러지
그런데 왜 제시카도 거기 있었지?
Why was Jessica even there?
셰퍼드 부부는 다른 사람들에겐
완벽한 부부처럼 보였어
Timmy. The Shepherds, to the world
they looked like the perfect couple.
- 겉모습에 대한 격언이 있죠
- 겉모습에 속을 수 있다는 말인가?
You know what they say about looks.
They can be deceiving?
겉모습에 죽을 수 있다는 것이죠
They can kill.
자막제작 - 네이트 C.S.I. 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
번역수정/맞춤법교정
손성봉(shon9795@nate.com)
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)